[music]
[Instructor] Cool, so, we have this
cool smoke explosion
here that we can Play,
but one of the things we need
to do is actually make it Play
when the Player runs into
one of our Obstacles.
So If I time it right, [explosion]
so something like that, pretty close.
The computer can probably do
it better than I can
so we'll just have the computer do it.
So we can actually do that by going
into our PlayerController Script.
And then in our PlayerController Script,
very similar to how we got
our Components
for our Rigidbody and our Animator,
we'll do something similar.
In this case,
because our Particle System
is actually outside
of our Player Components
we'll make this a "public...
ParticleSystem..."
And we'll call
this the "explosionParticle."
So now this'll create
one of those variables
in our Component that we
need to drag
something on to.
So we'll do that later.
Now in our PlayerController
if() statement
whenever a Player runs into an Obstacle
this is where we're actually
going to make
our explosionParticle happen.
So, when the Player dies,
we can add another line,
and we have the explosionParticle now,
and we can actually
just "Play()" the Particle.
And so that entire animation
Effect will just play
as soon as it hits this line of code.
So, we run into an Obstacle,
Game Over happens, Player dies,
and it'll Play the explosion
Effect that we have.
And then, in Unity,
just make sure that when you go
to your Player Object
you take your explosion smoke,
and drag it down
to the PlayerController Script,
and drop it into the Explosion Particle.
So now, when we press Play...
when the Player runs into an Obstacle
we should see a big puff of smoke.
Perfect, that's exactly
what we were looking for.
So, now what you're going to do,
is in your PlayerController Script,
you're going to create a public
variable that is a Particle System,
and we'll call it explosion Particle.
And then in our OnCollisionEnter()
method,
where we actually end the game
by running into an Obstacle,
we're just going to call
that explosionParticle variable,
and Play it so it Plays the animation.
And then, in Unity,
just make sure to click and drag
on your explosion smoke
in your Hierarchy,
drop it into the Particle
in your PlayerController Script,
and then when you Play the game,
and run it you should see
a big puff of smoke when you run
into an Obstacle.
Now it's your turn.
[music]